MARCOS VALDENI LUCAS

Dublin, Ireland

e-mail: marcosvaldeni@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>marcos-v-lucas</u> YouTube: <u>youtube.com/channel</u>
GitHub: <u>marcosvaldeni</u> Portfolio: <u>portfolio-marcosvaldeni</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE:

IT graduate with a bachelor's degree in Information Technology from CCT College Dublin, Ireland. With 2 years' experience in Web development using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Currently enrolled in a Bootcamp hands-on code learning NodeJS, ReactJS and React Native technologies and the entire ecosystem around these tools, from zero to deploy. Including automated testing, continuous integration, publishing in stores and all libraries and frameworks. Looking for a position as Junior Frontend Developer.

SKILLS

- Programming: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, React Native, NodeJS, Git, MySQL, Postgres, TypeScript, Linux, PHP, GitHub.
- Other applications: Figma, Sony Vegas, Visual Studio
- Languages: Fluent English / Native Portuguese

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Nov 2020 - Present Rocketseat

Bootcamp GoStack

Practical and intensive Bootcamp focus on NodeJS, ReactJS, and React Native technologies.

2016 - 2019 CCT - College Dublin, 30-34 Westmoreland Street, Dublin 2, Ireland

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Results: 1.1 Distinction

Core Modules: Advanced Database - XML, MySQL Server, PostgreSQL, and ER Diagram.

Object-Oriented Constructs

Interactive Web App

Cloud Computing Google Platform Web Development | Web Design

Thesis: "hotBerry" web application that uses a Raspberry Pi computer connected

which allows remote control for users to switch ON/OFF the hot water.

CAREER EXPERIENCE

2021

During this time, whilst looking for a Junior Frontend position. I also attend to on ongoing Online Bootcamp. Additionally, I have been practising code and create few web projects.

Aug - Dec 2020 Web Developer Trainee

3D Issue

• Developing CSS and HTML responsive layouts for digital Flipbooks inside React environment.

Sep 2019 - April 2020 Volunteer Mentor

CCT COLLEGE DUBLIN

- Helped undergraduate students and supported Lecturers in class of 45 students, to clarify subjects such as web designer, Java, CSS, HTML and PHP and guidance the students.
- Provided support directly to extra classes for undergraduate IT students to develop codes and solve issues in their academic projects related to the subjects above.

May 2015 - July 2020 General Cleaner

NOONAN SERVICE GROUP LTD

• Cleaning duties in offices.

Mar - April 2015

• During this time, I moved from Brazil to Ireland, spent time establish residence in Dublin and started learning English in a school and discover the Irish culture.

Sep 2014 - Feb 2015 AutoCAD Designer

GREEN ENVIRONMENTAL MODULE

- Provided new multimedia product concepts, structured budgets, and designed the model of the building which predict the number of materials necessary and helped the company planned and execute the project.
- Designed animations and illustrations with multimedia presentations using Corel Draw, and print designs for marketing advertising.
- Created unique designs exceeding client expectations; constructed drawings using AutoCAD software, and 3D renderings in Sketchup.

Nov 2012 - Jun 2014 Web Developer

DERHAUS TRAINING CENTRE

- Developed Frontend and Backend website architecture plus applications, designed user interactions on web pages. Build servers and databases for functionality.
- Contributed to the development of websites with Admin and online sales System.
- Developed websites and integrated internal system using PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and AJAX.

Jul 2011 – Nov 2012 IT Teacher

DERHAUS TRAINING CENTRE

- Teach groups between 10 to 16 elderly students in weekly classes on how to use computers and their basic functionalities.
- Training group of maximum 16 students on Windows Operating System, Office Pack, CorelDRAW, Photoshop, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP fundamentals.
- Designed and developed appropriate computer instructional material using PowerPoint slides and video guides.
- Determined and troubleshoot technological services for staff members like computer maintenance and solve networking connections.

Jan 2010 – Jun 2011 Technical Support

STARCOLOR ALUMINIUM PROTECTION AND DECORATION

- Maintained the intern server (Linux) as the server required lines of command once was not with graphic interface.
- Changed memory card of machines, network card and installed new terminals with the specific server used by the company when someone new was hired.